raspberry pi a computer that fits in the palm of your
raspberry pi一款可放在手掌中的电脑，
hand with a price tag as low as five dollars the idea was born
价格低至 5 美元 这个想法诞生
in 2006 and the first commercial unit was launched in 2012
于 2006 年，第一个商业单元于 2012 年推出
and since then it's evolved into one of the best selling computers in the world
，从那时起，它发展成为全球最畅销的电脑之一 世界
it's named raspberry because computer companies like to name themselves after
之所以将其命名为 raspberry，是因为计算机公司喜欢以
fruit and pie for the python programming language
水果和派来命名自己，因为 Python 编程语言
not only is the computer tiny but it can also be quite powerful
不仅计算机很小，而且它还可以非常强大
with a quad core processor and up to eight gigabytes of ram they're great for
，具有四核处理器和高达8 GB 的内存，它们非常适合
building your own iot prototypes robots security cameras web servers and many
构建自己的物联网原型 机器人安全摄像头 网络服务器和许多
other fun projects when you unbox your raspberry pi 4
其他有趣的项目当你打开你的树莓派 4 时，
you'll notice a bunch of little chips and connectors
你会注意到中心有一堆小芯片和连接
in the center we have our cpu and ram that is the brain of the operation
器 我们有我们的 cpu 和 ram，它们是
nearby is the wi-fi bluetooth module that can wirelessly connect to the
附近的操作大脑 顶部是可以无线连接外部世界的wi-fi蓝牙模块
outside world at the top we have a general purpose
我们有一个通用
input output connector for connecting other electrical devices
输入输出连接器用于连接其他电气设备
to the right we have an ethernet connection along with four usb ports
在右边，我们有一个以太网连接，底部有四个 USB
on the bottom we have an audio jack two connect speakers or headphones
端口，我们有一个音频插孔，两个连接扬声器或耳机，
a csi camera connector for building your own custom camera
一个 csi 摄像头连接器，用于构建您自己的自定义摄像头
micro hdmi ports for connecting multiple monitors
micro hdmi 端口，用于连接多个显示器
and finally a usb c port to provide power to the computer but most
，最后一个 USB c 端口连接到为计算机提供电源，但最
importantly flip the raspberry pi over to find the
重要的是翻转树莓派以找到
micro sd slot think of it as a hard drive that
微型 sd 插槽将其视为包含与硬件接口所需的操作系统的硬盘驱动器，
contains the operating system required to
interface with the hardware you can use the raspberry pi like a normal desktop
您可以像使用普通台式计算机一样使用树莓
computer by connecting a keyboard mouse and
派连接 一个键盘鼠标和
monitor when you power it up the first time you can install
显示器，当你第一次启动它时，你可以安装
any operating system you'd like but most beginners will take advantage of the
任何你想要的操作系统，但大多数初学者会利用
noobs installer which installs a flavor of linux called
noobs 安装程序，它安装了一种称为 raspberry pi os 的 Linux 风格，
raspberry pi os now that you're in you can program it to
因为你在你里面 可以对其进行编程以
take over the world you might connect some leds to the gpio header then
接管世界您可以将一些 LED 连接到 gpio 标头然后
control them with a python script or you might add a camera then connect to wi-fi
使用 python 脚本控制它们，或者您可以添加一个摄像头然后 c 连接到 Wi-Fi
to build your own home security system from scratch
从头开始构建您自己的家庭安全系统 可
the possibilities are limited only by your imagination
性仅限于您的想象力 这
this has been raspberry pi in 100 seconds if you enjoy these short videos
100 秒的树莓派 如果您喜欢这些短片，请确
please make sure to hit the like button and subscribe
保点击“赞”按钮并订阅它真
it really helps out and if you want to see more raspberry pi content let me
的很有帮助 如果您想查看更多树莓派内容
know in the comments thanks for watching and i will see you
，请在评论中告诉我，谢谢观看，我们
in the next one
下期再见